<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[F-Stop's Octopress Experience]]></title>
  <link href="http://fstop.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://fstop.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-04-30T22:43:37-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://fstop.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Your Name]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Keep The Ball Bouncing]]></title>
    <link href="http://fstop.github.com/blog/2013/04/30/keep-the-ball-bouncing/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://fstop.github.com/blog/2013/04/30/keep-the-ball-bouncing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Wherein I write something <del>very</del> short before bed</h2>

<p>So I was listening to the <a href="http://shotalkshow.com">Shop Talk Show</a>, as I frequently do while doing dishes late at night. I really depend on web dev podcasts to get me through the daily monotony of dishes, which there are a lot of in our house, because we prepare most of our meals at home. But I digress&#8230;</p>

<p>So I was listening to Shop Talk Show, and, as usual, got a nice little nugget of information about something that I use on pretty much every site: <a href="http://modernizr.com">modernizr</a>.</p>

<p>Modernizr has become so common, and is baked into my preferred WordPress starter theme, <a href="https://github.com/eddiemachado/bones">Bones</a>. But Chris &amp; Dave made a great point: modernizr does lots of &#8220;stuff&#8221; in the background, testing to see if the browser supports dozens and dozens of features. It can be up to ~40k (uncompressed), but beyond that it is injecting and removing things from the page and doing all sorts of other things in the milliseconds before the page is rendered.</p>

<p>They cautioned that it&#8217;s not always necessary to use it, and pointed out that you can build your own version of modernizr that tests only for the things you want it to. In fact the download page pretty much forces you to do this.</p>

<p>It got me thinking. How often do I actually use modernizr? So far I have only used it for the CSS classes it spits out on the <code>&lt;html&gt;</code> element, which indicate whether or not a crappy old browser supports something, allowing for fallbacks to be used in the CSS. For example:</p>

<pre><code>    .thing{
        color: #fff;
        text-shadow: 1px 1px 1px rgba(0,0,0,.4);

        .no-border-radius &amp;{
            color: #373737
        }
     }
</code></pre>

<p>And when I think about it, I rarely use modernizr. Usually only once or twice per project, sometimes not at all. Yet I haven&#8217;t really thought about not using it, or perhaps building my own stripped down version at the end of the project, only including the feature tests I need.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ll definitely be thinking about this going forward, though. How about you?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[And another thing]]></title>
    <link href="http://fstop.github.com/blog/2013/04/04/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-04T21:14:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://fstop.github.com/blog/2013/04/</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Down with perfectionism</h3>

<p>I closed my laptop as I usually do this time of night, but instead of the usual feelings of mild anxiety from &#8220;wasting&#8221; another hour browsing reddit, I felt good. I felt good even though I didn&#8217;t work on my website, even though I didn&#8217;t work on a project.</p>

<p>I thought about it and realized it was because I was doing something for the sake of doing it, and letting go of the need for it to be and look perfect.</p>

<p>My site is perpetually not finished because I want it to be perfect. But it&#8217;s hard to make it perfect, so I put it off.</p>

<p>But this thing I&#8217;m doing right here is simple. I like it. Unfortunately I am no longer a single young man with all the time in the world. So KP (kitchen patrol) and bed beckon&#8230;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[This is a post. This is only a post.]]></title>
    <link href="http://fstop.github.com/blog/2013/04/02/bad-ace/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-02T11:16:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://fstop.github.com/blog/2013/04/02/bad-ace</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Wow, does this actually work?</h3>

<p>So, it turns out that writing a blog post in markdown is actually kind of nice. I enjoy the simplicity of it. And the FoldingText app makes it even nicer. I feel I am about as close to a typewriter as I can get while working on a $3000+ shiny metal laptop.</p>

<p>Figuring out the templating process is a bit daunting, and I find myself wondering if I should be devoting time to yet another new thing, while my &#8220;real&#8221; website, <a href="http://fstopdesign.com">fstopdesign.com</a> languishes in its perpetually half finished state like the house of a contractor.</p>

<p>The designer in me badly wants to tweak and customize the design of this default template, but that&#8217;s where I stop short because I know I could spend days figuring out this system, and is it worth it?</p>

<p>I have finally gotten to a pretty fluent state with my WordPress theming and developing knowledge, so why would I want to go off and start over with something that&#8217;s totally new, and rather difficult to learn?</p>

<p>Well, the big attraction for me is the simplicity of the static site that these static site generators generate. I love WordPress, but honestly, the thought of serving up some simple, static, pre rendered HTML/CSS/JS files is very appealing after dealing with with the dynamic soup that is WordPress.</p>

<p>Then there is the fact that I&#8217;m actually, at this exact moment, doing something that I have been thinking about doing, urging myself to do, feeling bad that I have not been doing for a very long time: writing. It&#8217;s funny, I can feel my hands getting a bit tired from this little bit of typing. But it feels great!</p>

<p>Probably what I&#8217;ll do is let my inner designer suffer slowly as I continue to use this Octopress thing to write with first and figure out how to make it look like my own thing later.</p>

<p>I have to say, publishing a post with a <code>rake deploy</code> command in the terminal feels kinda cool.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
